# Macros

Macros are nothing more than a recorded sequence of keystrokes.
These keystrokes are actually saved in registers.

# Macro best practices
1. Normalize the cursor position:
    0
2. Perform edits and operations.
3. Position your cursor to enable easy replays.
    j
4. Stop recording with q

^[ = <ESC>
^M = <ENTER>

# Record a macro into the register, type q and register name.
qa

When finished recording, type q to quit.

# Playback macro 
[count]@[REGISTER]
5@a

# Repeat last played macro
@@

# Append to a macro
q {CAPITAL_REGISTER}
qA
Then, type command and hit q to finish the update
J

# View register
:reg a

# Substitute
An easy way to replace the double quotes with single quotes is to use the substitute command

eg
qd
:s/"/'/g<ENTER>
:s/(//<ENTER>
:s/)//<ENTER>
:s/ =>/,/<ENTER>
:s/usa/USA/<ENTER>
j
q

# Apply the macro to the exact range
:set nu - to turn on the line numbering
:[range] normal @{REGISTER}
eg
:27,35 normal @q

# Change current line thru end of the file
.,S

# Create a macro over multiple lines

# Insert something at the beginning of the macro
You can paste the contents of your register, modify and yank it back into the register
"ap
Make a change
"ay$ - go to 'a' register and yank it to the end

# Verify replaying
"a

# Saving Macros
1. viminfo file - don't overwrite
    .viminfo (for Mac and Linux)
2. vimrc file
    .vimrc

eg (use equal sign and a single quote, then paste)
let @d = ' then "dp then a' (to append single quote)

# Add TODO to t register in vimrc
# add the literal ^[, Ctrl-v then hit <ESC>
let @t = 'ITODO: Ctrl-v^hit<ESC>j'

Should look like this
let @t = 'ITODO: ^[j'

If you have single quotes that are in your macro, you can surround the let statement with double quotes.


















